Hyunyoung Kim

Gwangju, S. Korea

+82 10 5050 0720

hyuny.kim1@gmail.com

http://hyunyoungkim.com

Summary

My research interests lie on Human-Computer Interaction, especially sensors, actuators, mobile, in wearable and tabletop environment. I have a passion of making interactions easier and more enjoyable with both physical and visual interfaces. I have developed a novel gesture keyboard capable of sensing hand gestures over the keyboard using IR-based sensor arrays. I also designed user scenarios and interfaces for smart home and digital wallet service in Samsung Electronics. As a researcher of CNU, my current research projects investigate exploring interactions based on conductive fabrics and thread.

Education

KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology), Daejon, South Korea	Mar 2009 – Feb 2011
Master of Science, Digital Media Program, Advisor: Minsoo Hahn	

Sungkyunkwan University, Suwon, South Korea Mar 2004 – Feb 2009 Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering, GPA: 3.93/4.5

Park University, MO, USA
Transferred student

Jan 2007 – May 2007

Honors and Awards

Employee of Month, Samsung Electronics, 3 times	2011 - 2013
Korea National Robot Soccer Mirosot League, 3rd place, Korea Robot Soccer Association	Aug 2005
Champions League MiroSot Small League, 1st place, Kangnam University Korea	Feb 2005
National scholarship, KAIST	2009 - 2010
Merit based 4 year full scholarship for Bachelor degree, Sungkyunkwan University	2004 - 2008

Publications

Hyunyoung Kim, Gesture-Recognition Interface with Keyboard Embedded IR Modules, Master's Thesis '11

Hyunyoung Kim, Kuenhwan Kwak, Jongwoo Jung, Insik Myung, Minsoo Hahn, Tablaction: collaborative brainstorming system with stylus-fingertip interactions on tablet PCs, <u>VRCAI '10</u>

Hyunyoung Kim, Donghoon Lee, Jeehyung Lee, Personalized Comment Spam Filtering Using Clustering, KIIS '08

Patents

Hyun-Young Kim, Hee-Won Jung, Device and method for transmitting electronic key thereof, US20140115493 A1

Hyun-Young Kim, Tae-hwan WI, Method and device for transmitting information related to event, US20140075329 A1

Hyun-Young Kim, Tae-hwan WI, User terminal device and system for performing user customized health management, and methods thereof, US20130268292 A1

Sung-Jin Park, **Hyun-Young Kim**, User terminal, external apparatus, data transceiving system, and data transceiving method, US20140128031 A1

Eun-young Lim, **Hyun-Young Kim**, Yeon-hee ROH, Joo-kyung Woo, Young-shil Jang, User terminal device for providing electronic shopping service and methods thereof, US20130332228 A1

Jae-Woo Ko, Tae-hwan WI, Hee-Won Jung, **Hyun-Young Kim**, Bo-seok MOON, Management server and method for controlling device, user terminal apparatus and method for controlling device, and user terminal apparatus and control method thereof, US20130268998 A1

Other Research

A pressure sensitive tablet and its practical uses, software implementation	2010
Yo! Run! – Mobile running assistant system using foot sensor and mobile application, user	2010
research and software implementation	
A remotely music-controlling tumbler, implementation with Arduino and Processing	2009

Professional Experience

Chonnam National University, Gwangju, South Korea Researcher

Nov 2014 – Current

Association for Vertical Farming, Munich, Germany Web Designer/Developer

Dec 2013 - May 2014

Samsung Electronics, Suwon, South Korea UX Designer, User Research & UI Design, UX Center, DMC Research Centers

Feb 2011 – May 2013

- Smart Home service & UI design. Part of the mobile and TV interfaces was demonstrated on '13 IFA. The UX, which is harmonizing 3rd party products and worldwide users was designed strategically based on the global user research and usability test.
- · Concept generation and UI design for Samsung's first Smart LED mobile application.
- Mobile Wallet project, which is showed in MWC '13. Designed UIs for merchants' part, managed card reader appressory design and led user research.
- Ideation process consulting and patent development with patent specialists and engineers. Related patents are pending.
- · Patent task force for new health devices and services collaborating with engineers.
- Performed a medical device design with IDEO and new business development division;
 Learned IDEO's research know-how in paired observation, interview, and observational sharing.

Samsung Software Membership, Seoul, South Korea Student Researcher, Interaction Design & Prototyping Jan 2010 – Dec 2010

KOREA MART, Japan

Jan 2006 – Feb 2006

Intern, Homepage & shopping mall development

Skills

User Research Usability test, task observation, heuristic analysis, home visiting, interview, GOMS, wizard of

oz, survey design and data analysis

Languages & APIs C++, Java, C, C#, WPF, Processing, Windows Mobile, HTML, CSS, Javascript, MySQL,

Google Map API

Development Tools Visual Studio, Eclipse IDE, XCode

Engineering Arduino, circuit design

UX DesignIllustrator, Photoshop, Axure, Omnigraffle, Balsamiq, Flowella, ideation, personas, scenarios,

wireframe, userflow

Teaching and Service

Mentor	Women's science thesis competition for undergraduates and high school students	2011
Instructor	Designing circuits, basics from soldering to implementing, for undergraduate lab interns	2010
Instructor	Trends of human sensing technology, in course seminar	2008

Language Skills

English Spoken and written proficiency in English

German Basic grammatical and conversational knowledge of German

Korean Native

References

Minsoo Hahn	Professor at KAIST	mshahn2@kaist.ac.kr
Jinsul Kim	Professor at CNU	jsworld@chonnam.ac.kr
Sung Park	Senior Researcher at Samsung Electronics	spica7601@gmail.com